Lemesa Yadeta Aga



Contact

Address:

Addis Ababa.

Phone:

0927874515/0915764334

Email:

<u>Lemu4515@gmail.com</u> Portfolio

lemesayadeta.netlify.app

Languages

- Amharic
- English

Hobbies

- Sport
- Reading And
- Watching movies.

Reference

Mr Mulugeta Getachew Phone: - 0914196411

Lecture -Dire Dawa University.

Mr. Eyasu D. Phone:-0912918400

Chair, Computer Science Head - Dire Dawa University.

Summary

I graduated with a BSc degree in Computer Science from Dire Dawa University since July/2019. Over Six Years Experienced Different position in Dire Dawa University, National Election Board of Ethiopia and Moti Engineering PLC.

Skill Highlights

- Network Configuration And Installation
- Troubleshooting
- problem solving

- Technical Support
- Communication
- Hardware and Software installation

Experience

Chief Technical Assistance I- August 16/2021 to present Dire Dawa University

- Teaching and providing technical support for the Students.
- Installing and configuring computer hardware, and software
- Monitoring and maintaining computer systems and networks.

Senior Technical Assistance – July 29/2019 to August 16/2021

Dire Dawa University

- Installing and configuring computer hardware, and software
- Monitoring and maintaining computer systems and networks.
- Responding in a timely manner to service issues and requests

IT Supervisor - February 2021 - July 2021

National Election Board of Ethiopia

- Installing and configuring computer hardware, and software, systems, networks, printers, and scanners.
- Monitoring and maintaining computer systems and networks responding in a timely manner to service issues and requests

ICT Technician Analyst II- December 2023- April 2024 Moti Engineering PLC

• Make sure an organization's computers, printers and copier and the deployed systems are functioning and meet the needs of the organization

Data Management - July 2020 - March 2021(Voluntary Service)

Dire Dawa Administration Health Bureau

- Conduct and Support All data collector, registry, analysis, and reporting activities with the dire Dawa regional laboratory.
- Collect, Compile, sort, and maintain Covid -19 Test Records.
- Secure The Data with appropriate security measures.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science July 04- 2019 at Dire Dawa University.

Certifications

- ➤ Level -3 for Hardware and Networking Service (COC)
- > Cisco CCNA certification
- > Solve it certification of participation
- > Computer Software and Hardware maintenance.
- ➤ Driving license Automotive & Taxi 2